Rage of Bahamut
TEMPLE ARK
ドォーン！
-What is it?
-Enemy attack!
(ｱｰｸｴﾝｼﾞｪﾙ)なんだ？
≫(軍神)敵襲！
Could it be the demons?
魔の者でしょうか？
(ｱｰｸｴﾝｼﾞｪﾙ)いや➡
No, they should not have the forces necessary
to be attacking our sanctuary.
今の魔族に
我らの神殿を襲う力などない｡
グオォーー！
(軍神たち)うわっ！
ドォーン！
It's the humans!
(軍神)
人間だ！ 人間が攻めてきたぞ～！
The humans are attacking!
(軍神)ぐわぁ～！
(軍神)ぐっ！
ザシュ！
(ｱｰｸｴﾝｼﾞｪﾙ)ぐっ…
やはり 貴様ら 人間たちか？
I knew it was you vile humans.
You use the powers forbidden by the gods...
我ら神々が禁じた力を使い➡
...and continue to attack our holy sanctuaries.
聖なる神殿を襲い続ける
おごり高き者どもよ…｡
You arrogant creatures.
Do not make the mistake of believing
that you humans will be able...
その力 お前たち人間が
使いこなせるなどと➡
...to handle such power.
決して思うな…｡
ドスッ！
The age of man revering the gods has ended.
(ｼｬﾘｵｽ17世)人が神を崇める時代は
終わったのだ｡
Royal Capital Anatae
ボオッ！
(ﾏﾌｨｱﾎﾞｽ)ふん｡➡
They've all got big wings.
どいつもこいつも 羽が大きいな｡
ご心配なく｡
お渡しするときには➡
Rest assured, they will be cleanly removed
before you receive them.
きれいさっぱり
切り取っておきますので｡
≪ブスッ！
≪(ﾏﾌｨｱ)ぐあっ！
ブスッ！
(ﾏﾌｨｱ)ぐおっ！
ヒヒィーン！
なんだ!?
What's going on?
ひぃ～！
バリン！
くっ… 出やがった｡
ヤツだ 包帯悪魔だ！
It's him. It's the rag demon.
う… うわぁ～！ ぐわっ！
くそったれ！
だあっ！ くそったれが～｡
Curses!
Take this.
カモン デーモン！
ブスッ！
ドォーン！
(ﾏﾌｨｱﾎﾞｽ)うっ うわっ…｡
グオォーー！
グオォー…
W-- Wait. Don't kill me.
ま… 待て！
やめろ 殺さないでくれ｡
(ﾃﾞｨｱｽ)静まれ！
Hold there!
ヒヒィーン！
-Morning.
-Good morning.
(ﾆｰﾅ･ﾄﾞﾗﾝｺﾞ)おっはよう！
(市民)おはよう｡
おはよう！
おう おはよう！
-Good morning.
おはよう｡
-Morning.
-Good morning.
Good morning.
おはよう｡
あっ…｡ おはよう｡
(ﾊﾟﾝ屋)おう おはようさん｡
-Morning.
-Oh, good morning.
You're full of energy this morning, Nina.
ニーナは 今日も朝から元気だな｡
Yeah, I can't wait to get to work.
うん｡ 今日も元気に働きますよ｡
Good. I have a present for such a diligent worker.
よし そんな働き者には
こいつをやろう｡
Take it with you.
持ってきな｡ ほい！
うわっ｡
ありがとう！
Thanks!
んん～ いい匂い｡
ふふふっ ふふっ｡
Smells so good.
相変わらず いい食べっぷりだ｡
You really love to eat.
-Lord Charioce has returned!
-He's returned?
(市民)シャリオス様が お戻りだ！
(市民)お戻りになられたか！
(ﾊﾟﾝ屋)おっ こうしちゃいらんねぇ｡
えっ？
Oh, I don't want to miss it.
(市民)シャリオス様 万歳！
(市民たち)万歳！ 万歳！ 万歳！
All hail Lord Charioce!
剣の刃こぼれ修理で忙しくなるぜ｡
I'm going to be busy repairing their swords.
その前に 凱旋の祝いだ｡
But first, they'll need to celebrate their triumphant return,
which means a big order of meats.
肉の注文が たくさん来るぞ～｡
(ﾊﾟﾝ屋)ありがてぇなぁ｡
We're so blessed.
ねえ 何が ありがたいの？
Hey, what's so great about this?
The reason I'm able
to share the bread like that with you...
お前さんに そうやって
パンを恵んでやれるのも➡
...is all thanks to Lord Charioce XVII, King of Anatae.
アナティ王
シャリオス17世のおかげなんだぞ｡
えっ？
シャリオス様のお力で➡
The capital has prospered so much
under Lord Charioce.
王都は とても豊かになった｡➡
You should be grateful to the king.
お前さんも
王様に感謝するんだな｡
うん 感謝する｡
I'm grateful then.
ふん｡
Check that--
ふぅ～｡
(絵描き)そこの君！➡
You there.
Up here.
こっちだよ こっち！
ん？
(絵描き)
上へ来て 足場を動かすのを➡
Could you come up here
and help me move this scaffolding?
手伝ってくれないか？
はい｡
Okay.
Where do you want it?
どこに置く？
あっ ああ… ここに｡
Right here.
よっと｡
(絵描き)おわっ｡➡
You're quite strong. I haven't seen you around.
Are you new to Anatae?
随分 力持ちだね｡
見ない顔だけど 最近 王都に？
うん｡
(絵描き)名前は？
-Yeah.
-What's your name?
Nina.
ニーナよ｡
ニーナか｡ いい名前だ｡
"Nina." That's a good name.
どこから来たんだ？
あっ…｡
Where are you from?
(絵描きの声)どっから来たんだ？
どっから来たんだ？
Where are you from?
What does that matter?
どこでもいいじゃない！
あっ… どうした？
What's wrong?
あっ
あの人たち すごい働き者ね！
Anyway, those people over there
are really hard workers.
ん？ あれは 人じゃない｡
Those aren't people.
(見張り)休むんじゃねぇ！
人じゃないの？
-Keep pulling!
-They're not people?
I wouldn't think about them too much.
(絵描き)彼らのことは
あまり気にしない方がいい｡
These are just the times we live in.
今は そういう時代だから｡
えっ？
ドクン ドクン ドクン…(鼓動)
ああ～！ いけない いけない！
No! No!
You're pretty bashful, aren't you, Nina?
(絵描き)ニーナは
随分 恥ずかしがり屋だね｡
That's a big picture.
大きな絵｡
Is that the king?
あれは 王様？
(絵描き)ん？ そうだ｡
That's right.
I saw the king for the first time this morning.
今朝 町で初めて 王様を見たよ｡
シャリオス１７世は➡
Everyone was saying that
Charioce XVII is a great king.
偉い王様だって みんな言ってた｡
あっ あれは？
What's that?
That's Bahamut.
あれは バハムートだよ｡
バハムート…｡
Bahamut?
How old were you 10 years ago?
１０年前
ニーナは いくつだった？
Six.
６つ｡
(絵描き)それなら覚えているね➡
Then you should remember Bahamut.
バハムートのことは｡
Yeah.
うん…｡ １０年前➡
Ten years ago,
the fireballs rained down on my village too.
私の里にも 火の玉が降った｡
Bahamut turned the continent of Mistarcia
into a wasteland.
(絵描き)バハムートによって➡
大陸 ミスタルシアは
荒野と化した｡➡
Those who lived through it
will undoubtedly never forget the fear of Bahamut.
生き延びた者は 死ぬまで
ﾊﾞﾊﾑｰﾄの恐怖を忘れないだろう｡➡
And it was Charioce XVII who resurrected
the Royal Capital Anatae from that despair.
その絶望から
王都 アナティを復活させたのが➡
シャリオス１７世だ｡
その歴史なの？ この壁画は｡
And this mural is telling that history?
That's right. It's our king's great history.
(絵描き)
そうだ｡ 王の栄光の歴史だ｡➡
By the way, Nina,
did you come to the capital to earn money?
ところで ニーナは
王都に出稼ぎに来たのかい？
Yeah.
うん｡ お母さんに楽をさせたいの｡
I want to give my mom a better life.
While the capital gets to flourish,
my village has stayed poor these past 10 years.
王都は こんなに栄えてるのに➡
私の里は １０年前から
ずっと貧しいままなんだもの｡
It's not like the capital isn't without its problems.
(絵描き)王都だって そんなに
いいところばかりではないけどね｡
そうなの？
Really?
(観客)何やってんだ！
Kaisar.
カイザル｡
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)はっ｡
My Lord.
Look at them.
ヤツらを見ろ｡
They are fighting for their lives.
命を懸けて戦っている｡
I heard you allowed the rag demon
to escape again last night.
昨夜も
包帯悪魔を取り逃がしたらしいな｡
(ﾓﾝｽﾀｰ)フンッ！
(魔族)グワァー！
ウオォーー！
Do not disappoint me.
私を失望させるなよ｡
Yes, my Lord.
Hey, take care of this.
(兵士)おい 片づけろ｡
ハァ ハァ ハァ… グアァ…
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)ムガロ｡
Mugaro.
Rage of Bahamut
I'm home.
ただいま！
(ﾊﾝｻ)クワッ？
Don't give me that "I'm home" crap.
You've been crashing here for 10 days.
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)｢ただいま｣じゃねぇよ
もう１０日も居候しやがって｡
出ていけ！ バカ野郎｡
Get out of here already, you idiot.
(ﾊﾝｻ)まあまあ まあまあ
バッカス 落ち着いてください｡
Now, now, now. Calm down, Bacchus.
ここは賞金稼ぎの来る所だ｡
This is a place for bounty hunters.
Not a shelter for brats like you.
お前のようなガキの
預かり所じゃねぇ｡
私 賞金稼ぎだけど？
Excuse me, but I am a bounty hunter.
ええっ!?
首の一つも挙げたことねぇくせに｡
What? But you've never collected a single bounty.
そのうち
大物をしとめてやるんだ｡
Don't worry, I'll get me a big one sooner or later.
Someone so big it'll make you cry, boss.
元締めのあんたが
泣いて喜ぶような大物をね｡
それまでは ここにいる｡
But until then, I'll be staying here.
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)それは
お前が決めることじゃあねぇ｡
That's not up to you.
それに あんたたちなら
男だけど 全然平気だしね｡
Besides, even though you're guys,
it doesn't affect me at all.
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)はぁ…｡
(ﾊﾝｻ)クワッ…｡
Anyway, looks like this guy's bounty went up again.
そんなことより この賞金首
また賞金上がったんだね｡
Seems like nobody has been able to catch him.
(ﾊﾝｻ)
誰も捕まえられないみたいですね｡
ふ～ん｡
He doesn't look that strong.
そんな強そうには見えないけど｡
(ﾊﾝｻ)昨晩も
被害に遭ったらしいですよ｡➡
Apparently, he caused some trouble last night too.
奴隷商人や荒くれ者たちが
悪魔に ひどいことをすると➡
They say that he always appears
whenever slave traders and the like abuse any demons.
決まって現れるんですって｡
いいヤツなの？
Is he a good guy?
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)賞金首が
いいヤツなわけねぇだろ！➡
How can a bounty be a good guy, you idiot?
バカ野郎｡
私 こいつを捕まえてみよっかな｡
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)あっ そう｡
-Maybe I'll try catching this guy.
-That's nice.
この賞金で
お母さんを楽させるんだ｡
-I'll send the reward back to my mom.
-What now?
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)はい!?
それに➡
Besides, now I kind of want to meet this rag demon.
包帯悪魔に
会ってみたくなっちゃった｡
じゃあ 行ってきます！
I'll be off then.
(ﾊﾝｻ)あっ お嬢さん！
ほっとけ ハンサ｡
-Hold on!
-Let her go, Hamsa.
じゃあね｡
See you.
Honestly, since when do gods
have to put up with this kind of treatment?
ったく
いつから神は あんなガキに➡
なめられるように
なっちまったんだよ バッカ野郎｡
Idiots.
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)出てこい 包帯悪魔！
Come out, rag demon!
ドォーン！
(兵士たち)うわぁ～！
キン！
ヒヒィーン！
ドカッ！
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)うっ！
観念しろ 包帯悪魔｡
Surrender yourself, rag demon.
I see that you are still obnoxious.
(包帯悪魔)
相変わらず うっとうしいヤツだ｡
Now, where am I gonna find this demon?
どこいんだろ？ この悪魔｡
うわぁ～！
あれ？ 今の…｡
Was that...?
ふん～～！
待てぇ～～！
Wait!
≫待て！
Stop!
What is this?
(包帯悪魔)なんだ？ お前は｡
なんだとは何よ！
I'll tell you what this is.
You're my trophy.
あんたは私の獲物よ｡
どりゃあ～！
うっ… あれ？
あぁ…｡ ふん！
ガラン ガラン(看板が落ちる音)
あちゃ～｡ って…｡
(兵士)こっちだ！ 追え 追え～！
This way! After him!
≪ヒヒィーン
Are you okay?
≪(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)大丈夫か？
ん？
あっ いや…
ちょっと これが取れなくて｡
I can't seem to get this free.
-What is it?
-It's nothing!
どうした？
なんでもありません！
ゴン！
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)あ痛っ！
ああっ ごめんなさい…｡
I'm sorry.
Captain!
≪(ｱﾚｻﾝﾄﾞ)団長～！
ん？
Bye.
さよなら！
Are you hurt, sir?
(ﾃﾞｨｱｽ)団長！ おケガは？
くっ… 大丈夫だ｡
I'm fine.
Curses.
(ｱﾚｻﾝﾄﾞ)くそっ
あの女 包帯悪魔の仲間か？➡
Was that girl with the rag demon?
-After her! After the girl!
-Yes, my Lord.
追え！ あの女を追うのだ！
(騎士たち)はっ！
もう～
どこ行っちゃったんだろう？
Where did he run off to?
ねえ あんた！
Hey, you.
Do you see a demon in rags from up there?
そっから 包帯した悪魔 見える？
Then would you let me switch places with you?
じゃあ
その場所 私と代わってくれる？
ドォーン！
(一同)ああっ！
Found him.
あっ いた！
えっ 何？
-What?
-The girl on the tower is with him!
(ｱﾚｻﾝﾄﾞ)塔の上の女も仲間だ！➡
Don't let her get away!
逃がすな！ 撃て！
Fire!
ボオッ！
うわっ！
ドォーン！
うわぁ～！
(包帯悪魔)くそっ
なぜ あいつが攻撃されている？
Damn it. Why is she getting attacked?
ドォーン！
うわぁ～～！
Those wings....
あの羽は…｡
Mugaro, are you okay?
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)ムガロ 大丈夫… ん？➡
ううっ！ 誰だ 貴様は!?
Who the hell are you?
≫ボオッ！
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)ちっ｡➡
ドクン ドクン ドクン…
ドォーン！
ドドォーン‼
(一同)うわぁ～！
What is it?
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)なんだ!?
(ﾃﾞｨｱｽ)包帯悪魔が➡
Do you think the rag demon summoned it?
召喚したのでしょうか？
グオォー！
(兵士)近寄るな！ 撃て～！
(兵士)撃て 撃て～！
Hold your positions!
-Fire!
グオォーー！
ボオッ！
グルルル…
ヒヒィーン！
退け！ 撤退だ 退け！
Retreat! Fall back! Fall back!
グルルル… グオォーー！
カァー カァー カァー…
カァー カァー
ここ どこだろ？
Where am I?
(ﾘﾀ)おはよ｡
Good morning.
-It is I, Kaisar Lidfard!
-And Charioce XVII too.
-That was crude.
-What did you say?
Shall we say it together?
Next time on Rage of Bahamut: Virgin Soul,
"The Miserables."
I can't believe I pronounced it right.
Baha Soul!!
Baha Baha Baha Soul!
Tune in next time!